In previous videos, we talked
在以前的视频中我们谈到
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
about the gradient descent algorithm
关于梯度下降算法
and talked about the linear
梯度下降是很常用的算法
它不仅被用在线性回归上
regression model and the squared error cost function.
和线性回归模型、平方差成本函数
In this video, we're going to
在这段视频中.我们要
put together gradient descent with
将梯度下降
our cost function, and that
和成本函数结合
will give us an algorithm for
在后面的视频中 我们将用到此算法
并将其应用于具体的
linear regression for fitting a straight line to our data.
得到拟合直线的线性回归算法
So, this is
所以这就是
what we worked out in the previous videos.
我们在之前的影片中所做的工作
That's our gradient descent algorithm, which
这是梯度下降法.
should be familiar, and you
这你应该很熟悉
see the linear linear regression model
这就是线性回归模型
with our linear hypothesis and our squared error cost function.
线性假设和平方差成本函数。
What we're going to do is apply
我们将要做的就是
gradient descent to minimize
用梯度下降的方法
our squared error cost function.
最小化平方差成本函数
Now, in order to apply
为了
gradient descent, in order
梯度下降.为了
to write this piece of
这篇文章所写的
code, the key term
代码.关键术语
we need is this derivative term over here.
我们需要的是这个微分名词在这里。
So, we need to figure out
所以.我们需要弄清楚
what is this partial derivative term,
这是什么偏导数项.
and plug in the
并插上
definition of the cost
成本的定义
function J, this turns
函数J.轮流
out to be this "inaudible"
事情是这样的“难以弄清的”
equals sum 1 through M of
通过并购.相等于1的
this squared error
这个误差平方
cost function term, and all
代价函数区间.以及所有
I did here was I just
我没在这里.我只是
you know plugged in the definition of
你知道插入的定义中
the cost function there, and simplifying
并定义的成本函数
little bit more, this turns
有点多.这将
out to be equal to, this
是等于.这
"inaudible" equals sum 1 through M
“难以弄清”通过并购总和等于1
of tetha zero plus tetha one, XI
加tetha tetha零一.XI
minus YI squared.
减YI的平方。
And all I did there was took
这就是我所做的一切了
the definition for my hypothesis
我的假设的定义
and plug that in there.
和插在那里。
And it turns out we need
原来我们需要
to figure out what is
弄清楚什么是
the partial derivative of two
2的偏导数
cases for J equals
案件的J等于
0 and for J equals 1 want
0的J等于1想要
to figure out what is this
要弄清楚这是什么
partial derivative for both the
偏导数同时为
theta(0) case and the theta(1) case.
θ（0）的情况下.θ（1）的情况下。
And I'm just going to write out the answers.
我只是写出来的答案。
It turns out this first term simplifies
事实证明.这第一项简化
to 1/M, sum over
到1 / M.求和
my training set of just
只是我的训练
that, X(i)-  Y(i).
.X（I） -  Y（I）。
And for this term, partial derivative
而这个词.偏导数
with respect to theta(1), it turns
相对于θ（1）.它打开
out I get this term: -Y(i)X(i).
我得到了这个词：-Y（I） X（I）
Okay.
好吧。
And computing these partial
并计算这些局部
derivatives, so going from
微分工具.所以从
this equation to either
此方程为
of these equations down there, computing
出现了下滑.这些方程计算
those partial derivative terms requires some multivariate calculus.
这些偏导数项要求一些多元演算。
If you know calculus, feel free
如果你知道微积分.随意
to work through the derivations yourself
工作.通过自己的推导
and check take the derivatives
并检查采取的微分工具
you actually get the answers that I got.
你实际上得到.我得到的答案。
But if you are less
但如果你是少
familiar with calculus you don't
熟悉微积分.你不这样做
worry about it, and it
担心它.它
is fine to just take these equations
罚款只是采取这些方程
worked out, and you
制定出来的.和你
won't need to know calculus or
不需要知道微积分或
anything like that in order to
类似的东西.以
do the homework, so to implement gradient descent you'd get that to work.
做功课.所以你会得到那个工作实施梯度下降。
But so, after these definitions,
但是.这些定义之后.
or after what we've worked
或者我们工作后.
out to be the derivatives, which
是的微分物.
is really just the slope of
真的只是斜率
the cost function J.  We
的成本函数J.
can now plug them back into
现在可以将它们放回
our gradient descent algorithm.
我们的梯度下降算法。
So here's gradient descent, or
所以这里的梯度下降.或
the regression, which is going
回归.这是会
to repeat until convergence, theta 0
重复.直到收敛.θ0
and theta one get updated as,
和theta得到更新.
you know, the same minus alpha
你知道.相同的负阿尔法
times the derivative term.
次微分项。
So, this term here.
所以.这个词在这里。
So, here's our linear regression algorithm.
所以.这里是我们的线性回归算法。
This first term here that
这第一项.在这里.
term is, of course, just
长期.当然.只是
a partial derivative of respective
部分微分物的各自的
theta zero, that we worked on in the previous slide.
西塔零.我们曾在上一张幻灯片。
And this second term here,
而这第二个区间.
that term is just
这个词是刚刚的
a partial derivative with respect to
相对于偏导数
theta one that we worked out on the previous line.
西塔.我们摸索出上一行。
And just as a quick reminder,
而只是作为一个快速提醒.
you must, when implementing gradient descent,
你必须实施梯度下降时.
there's actually there's detail that, you
实际上有细节.你
know, you should be implementing
知道了.你应该执行
it so the update theta zero and theta one simultaneously.
所以更新THETA零和theta同时。
So, let's see how gradient descent works.
所以.让我们来看看梯度下降是如何工作的。
One of the issues we solved
我们解决的问题之一
gradient descent is that it can be susceptible to local optima.
梯度下降的是.它可以容易局部最优。
So, when I first explained gradient
所以.当我第一次解释梯度
descent, I showed you this picture
血统.我发现你这幅画
of it, you know, going downhill
它.你知道.下坡
on the surface and we
的表面上.我们
saw how, depending on where
看到了.这取决于
you're initializing, you can end up with different local optima.
你初始化.您可以与不同的局部最优。
You know, you can end up here or here.
你知道.你可以结束了.在这里或这里。
But, it turns out that
但是.事实证明.
the cost function for gradient
梯度的成本函数
of cost function for linear regression
成本函数进行线性回归
is always going to be
总是要
a bow-shaped function like this.
弓形这样的功能。
The technical term for this
技术术语
is that this is called a convex function.
是.这是一个凸函数。
And I'm not going
而且我不打算
to give the formal definition for what
什么.得到正式的定义
is a convex function, c-o-n-v-e-x, but
是一个凸函数.凸.但
informally a convex function
非正式的凸函数
means a bow-shaped function, you know, kind of like a bow shaped.
指弓形功能.你知道的.那种像一个弓形。
And so, this function doesn't
所以.这个功能不
have any local optima, except
任何局部最优.除
for the one global optimum.
一个全局最优。
And does gradient descent on
和梯度下降
this type of cost function which
这种类型的成本函数
you get whenever you're using linear
只要您是使用线性
regression, it will always convert
回归.它总是会转换
to the global optimum, because there are no other local optima other than global optimum.
到全局最优.因为有没有其他的本地最优以外的全局最优。
So now, let's see this algorithm in action.
所以.现在.让我们来看看这个算法在行动。
As usual, here are plots of
像往常一样.这里有地块
the hypothesis function and of
设定功能和
my cost function J.
我的成本函数J.
And so, let's see how
所以.让我们来看看如何
to initialize my parameters at this value.
我在这个值的参数初始化。
You know, let's say, usually you
你知道.让我们说.通常你
initialize your parameters at zero
初始化参数为零
for zero, theta zero and zero.
为0.θ0和零。
For illustration in this
如需插图
specific presentation, I have
具体的介绍.我有
initialised theta zero at
初始化的theta为零
about 900, and theta one at about minus 0.1, okay?
约900.和theta一个约零下0.1.好吗？
And so, this corresponds to H
等.这相当于为H
over X, equals, you know,
超过X.等于.你知道.
minus 900 minus 0.1 x
减去900减去0.1×
is this line, so out here on the cost function.
这条线.所以这里的成本函数。
Now if we take one
现在.如果我们采取一
step of gradient descent, we end
梯度下降的步骤.我们最终
up going from this point
从这个角度去
out here, a little
在这里.一点点
bit to the down left
位的上下左右
to that second point over there.
那边.第二点。
And, you notice that my line changed a little bit.
而且.你注意到我行改变了一点点。
And, as I take another step
而且.我采取的又一步骤
at gradient descent, my line on the left will change.
梯度下降.将改变我行左侧。
Right.
右。
And I have also
而且我也有
moved to a new point on my cost function.
移动到一个新的起点上我的成本函数。
And as I think further step
因为我觉得进一步加强
is gradient descent, I'm going
是梯度下降.我要去
down in cost, right, so
在成本下降.对.所以
my parameter is following
我的参数是继
this trajectory, and if
这个轨迹.并且如果
you look on the left, this corresponds
在左边.你看.这相当于
to hypotheses that seem
假设似乎
to be getting to be
越来越成为
better and better fits for the
更好更适合的
data until eventually,
直到最后的数据.
I have now wound up at the global minimum.
我现在已经卷绕在全局最小值。
And this global minimum corresponds to
这个全球最小对应
this hypothesis, which gives me a good fit to the data.
这一假说.这给了我一个很好的适合的数据。
And so that's gradient
所以这是梯度
descent, and we've just run
血统.我们刚刚运行
it and gotten a good
并得到了良好
fit to my data set of housing prices.
适合我的数据集的住房价格。
And you can now use it to predict.
现在你可以用它来预测。
You know, if your friend has a
你知道.如果你的朋友有
house with a
房子有一个
size 1250 square feet, you
尺寸1250平方尺.
can now read off the value
现在可以读出的值
and tell them that, I don't
并告诉他们.我不
know, maybe they can get
知道.也许他们可以得到
$350,000 for their house.
他们的房子35万美元。
Finally, just to give
最后.只是为了给
this another name, it turns out
这另一个名字.它的出现
that the algorithm that we
该算法.我们
just went over is sometimes
刚刚走过去.有时
called batch gradient descent.
称为批处理梯度下降。
And it turns out in machine
而事实证明.在机
learning, I feel like us machine
学习.我觉得像我们这样的机
learning people, we're not always
学习的人.我们并不总是
created has given me some algorithms.
创建给了我一些算法。
But the term batch gradient descent
但长期批次梯度下降
means that refers to the
装置.指的是
fact that, in every step
事实.即在每一步
of gradient descent we're looking
我们正在寻找梯度下降
at all of the training examples.
在所有的训​​练实例。
So, in gradient descent, you
所以.在梯度下降.
know, when computing derivatives, we're computing
知道.计算微分工具时.我们计算
these sums, this sum of.
这些钱.这笔钱的。
So, in every separate
所以.在每一个单独的
gradient descent, we end up
梯度下降.我们最终
computing something like this, that
计算这样的事情.那
sums over our M training examples.
总结我们的并购训练实例。
And so the term batch gradient
因此术语批处理梯度
descent refers to the fact
血统是指这样的事实
when looking at the entire batch
当看着整批
of training examples, and again,
训练样例.并再次.
this is really, really not
这是真的.真的不
a great name, but this is
一个伟大的名字.但是这是
what Machine Learning people call it.
机器学习的人称呼它。
And it turns out there are
原来有
sometimes other versions of
有时其他版本的
gradient descent that are not
梯度下降不
batch versions but instead do
批量版本.而是做
not look at the entire traning set
不看整个教育训练集
but look at small subsets
但看在小的子集
of the training sets at the time,
训练集的时候.
and we'll talk about those versions later in this course as well.
.我们会谈论这些版本在这个过程中也是如此。
But for now, using the algorithm
但就目前而言.使用该算法
you just learned, now we're
你刚才的教训.现在我们
using batch gradient descent, you
使用批处理梯度下降.
now know how to implement
现在知道如何实现
gradient descent, or linear regression.
梯度下降.或线性回归。
So that's linear regression with gradient descent.
所以线性回归梯度下降。
If you've seen advanced linear algebra
如果你看过了先进的线性代数
before so some you may
所以有些你可能之前
have taken a class with advanced
已经采取了先进的类
linear algebra, you might
线性代数.你可能会
know that there exists a solution
知道存在一个解
for numerically solving for the
为求解
minimum of the cost function
最低的成本函数
J, without needing to
J.而无需
use and iterative algorithm like gradient descent.
使用像梯度下降的迭代算法。
Later in this course we will
后来在这个过程中.我们将
talk about that method as
谈谈该方法作为
well that just solves for the
好.只是解决了
minimum cost function J without
没有最低成本函数J
needing this multiple steps of gradient descent.
需要多个步骤梯度下降。
That other method is called normal equations methods.
其他的方法被称为正规方程组的方法。
And, but in case you
..但如果你
have heard of that method, it turns
原来听说过该方法.
out gradient descent will
出梯度下降
scale better to larger data
更好地扩展到更大的数据
sets than that normal equals
等于比正常组
method and, now that
方法.现在
we know about gradient descent, we'll
我们知道梯度下降.我们会
be able to use it in
可以使用在
lots of different contexts, and we'll
很多不同的上下文中.我们将
use it in lots of different Machine Learning problems as well.
在不同的机器学习问题.以及大量的使用它。
So, congrats on learning
所以.恭喜学习
about your first Machine Learning algorithm.
关于你的第一个机器学习算法。
We'll later have exercises in
我们稍后将有演习
which we'll ask you to
我们会问你
implement gradient descent and
实施梯度下降法和
hopefully see these algorithms work for yourselves.
希望看到这些算法为自己工作。
But before that I first
但在此之前.我第一次
want to tell you in
想告诉你
the next set of videos, the
下一组视频.
first want to tell you about
首先要告诉你
a generalization of the gradient descent
梯度下降的泛化
algorithm that will make
算法.这将使
it much more powerful and I
它更强大.我
guess I will tell you about that in the next video.
我想我会告诉你.在接下来的视频。